dietclub.com.au 2017-12-24

# Privacy Policy

Home » Privacy Policy 

Your personal information is important to The Family Health Network.

The Family Health Network understands that the privacy of your personal information is very important to you. It is important to us too!

The following policies will govern how The Family Health Network manages your personal information and protects your privacy. This Privacy Policy is incorporated into and subject to our Terms of Use, which you should refer to for additional information relating to privacy issues.

## 1\. Collecting information about you

The Family Health Network will not collect or monitor personal information about you without your consent unless we consider it is necessary:

  * to comply with the law
  * to comply with our Terms of Use
  * to protect the rights and/or property of The Family Health Network, the Network, Network Users, Network Subscribers and Members or any other individual or entity, including members of the public
  * to reduce or avoid a threat to anyone's health, safety or wellbeing
  * to provide services to you

The Family Health Network will only collect personal information which has been obtained from you. The amount of information will depend on you! You may provide us or an Affiliate with information:

  * when you register with or subscribe to the Network or email lists
  * by identifying yourself when you use the Network
  * by forwarding us correspondence about yourself or feedback about the Network
  * by joining various mailing lists
  * by answering surveys or polls
  * by entering competitions or sweepstakes
  * by posting in our chat rooms, message boards and other areas

Public discussion areas on the Network are not private and are governed by the Terms of Use. Any information you post in such areas may be seen, collected and used by others and may result in unsolicited messages. The Family Health Network can not control this. You post at your own risk.

In the event of a complaint, we may receive personal information about you from other parties in our Network, other Users or third parties who may communicate information to us about you in relation to that complaint.

The Family Health Network uses Cookies and other tracking methods to allow the provision of certain services and to maximize your enjoyment of the Network. We do not link this information back to other information that you have provided to us and The Family Health Network does not store any information inside Cookies. Any collection of personal information other than that mentioned here, will require your consent.

Cookies are pieces of information transferred from a web site to your computer's hard disk for record-keeping purposes. Cookies do not personally identify Users, although they do identify a User's browser. Most Web browsers are set to accept Cookies, although you can reset your browser to refuse. 

Cookies and IP addresses can enhance your enjoyment of the Network by allowing us to recognize you and anticipate your requirements. Cookies allow you to store your password without the need to continually re-enter it.They allow us to tailor a Web site or a marketing message to provide you with information which is relevant to your particular interests. The Family Health Network gives you the option of subscribing to the Network and receiving enhanced services. Refusing to accept Cookies may prevent you from fully utilizing some of these services.

We also collect and store statistics and other information about the online activities of Users on an aggregate basis. This does not include personal information about you.

By recognizing all of our Users, how they use the Network and what they find interesting, we can focus our resources on features that are the most popular and beneficial to our Users and provide a continuously improving service for everyone!

You should be aware that The Family Health Network places advertising and other material on the Network which may originate from outside individuals or entities. In some cases, if you click on or view these advertisements or other material, a Cookie may be assigned by the relevant third party. The Family Health Network does not control these Cookies. 

Our website uses Google Analytics, a service which transmits website traffic data to Google servers in the United States. Google Analytics does not identify individual users or associate your IP address with any other data held by Google. We use reports provided by Google Analytics to help us understand website traffic and webpage usage.

Our website uses Google Analytics features based on Display Advertising such as Google Analytics Demographics and Interest Reporting. We also make use of Google Remarketing to display relevant ads tailored to you based on what parts of the site you have viewed.

By using this website, you consent to the processing of data about you by Google in the manner described in [Google's Privacy Policy](http://www.google.com/policies/privacy/) and for the purposes set out above. You can opt out of Google Analytics if you disable or refuse the cookie, disable JavaScript, or opt out of Google's use of cookies by visiting [Google's Ads Settings](http://www.google.com/settings/ads). Alternatively you can opt out of third-party vendor cookies by visiting the [Network Advertising Initiative opt out page](http://www.networkadvertising.org/managing/opt_out.asp).

## 2\. Use and Disclosure of Personal Information

The Family Health Network will not use or disclose any personal information about you without your consent or access your communications on the Network, unless we consider it is necessary:

  * to comply with the law
  * to comply with our Terms of Use
  * to protect the rights and/or property of The Family Health Network, the Network, Network Users, Network Subscribers and Members or any other individual or entity, including members of the public
  * to reduce or avoid a threat to anyone's health, safety or wellbeing
  * to provide services to you

The Family Health Network and its Affiliates recognize the trust you place in us when you provide us with personal information. The Network may sometimes disclose this information to an Affiliate or other individual or entity to facilitate the operation of the Network and the provision of User services. In these instances, we may explicitly tell you that the data we are collecting will be shared with third parties. In these cases those disclosures will override anything to the contrary in this Policy. We will not otherwise disclose your personal information without your consent. 

We use your information on an aggregated basis to do such things as operate and enhance the Network and sell and deliver advertising. We also use this data, both aggregated and personal, to enhance your on-site experience by displaying content and marketing messages that we believe will be of interest to you. We disclose aggregated information about the Network to third parties. 

Some online activities you choose to do necessarily lead to disclosure of your personal information to third parties, such as when you include your name and email address in a postcard or when you order merchandise. In these cases, again, your choice to disclose personal information is voluntary. 

We may share your personal information with third parties who provide services to our Network in order to enhance the functionality available to you as part of the Network, and to provide you with new products and services such as email and Member pages. We may also use your personal information to provide information to you, such as newsletters that you request or to personalize the Network in accordance with your requests. 

Under certain circumstances we may be forced to disclose information to the Government or third parties, or third parties may unlawfully intercept or access transmissions or private communications. In the event that we need to investigate or resolve possible problems or inquiries, you expressly acknowledge, agree and authorize The Family Health Network to disclose any information about you to private entities, law enforcement or other Government officials as we, in our sole discretion, believe necessary or appropriate.

## 4\. Promotional Email 

If you have indicated as such, The Family Health Network and/or third parties may from time to time, send e-mail messages to you which offer products and services, contain advertisements, promotions, subscriptions or registration-based services or other material. If you wish to discontinue receiving such email, please disable promotions via the 'Change your details' link on your The Family Health Network personal page or the relevant third party. Your preferences will then be updated immediately.

## 4\. Storage and Security of Personal Information

The Family Health Network will endeavour to take all reasonable steps to maintain the accuracy and security of any personal information we hold. The Family Health Network maintains its User information in a secured database to protect the privacy of your "Locator Information", that is, your name, email address, physical address, and/or other data that enables you to be personally identified.

The Family Health Network uses firewalls and Secure Socket Layer ("SSL") encryption technology to ensure the integrity and privacy of the information you pass to us via the Internet, however, to take advantage of this, you must utilize a browser that maintains 128bit encryption support. Where a Network service is provided from overseas, your information is kept in secure databases and is protected by The Family Health Network's security policies. Despite our best efforts, "Perfect Security" does not exist on the Internet.

Our employees and data processors are bound to respect the confidentiality of any personal information held by The Family Health Network. Despite this, The Family Health Network will not be held responsible for any events which arise from any unauthorized access to your personal information. You should take care to protect your own personal information, including but not limited to passwords and accounts. You should contact The Family Health Network immediately if you become aware of any unauthorized use of your account or any other breach of security. 

## 5\. Accessing, Changing and Deleting your Personal Information

You may at any time request a copy of your file from The Family Health Network. If you wish to change the information we have about you or have it deleted entirely please contact The Family Health Network. We will provide you with a copy of your file and do everything we reasonably can to alter or delete your information, unless we are required to maintain certain information for legal or other reasons. Please allow at least seven days for your request to be processed.

## 6\. Links to Other Web Sites

The Network provides links to Other Web sites which are not controlled by The Family Health Network. We are not responsible for the conduct of any individual or entity associated with these Other Web sites. You should familiarize yourself with the relevant Web site's Terms and Conditions and Privacy Policy before using their site or disclosing any of your personal information to them.

## 7\. Children on the Network

Children should always ask a parent or guardian for permission before sending any personal information over the Internet, whether to us or anyone else. This includes buying stuff!

We encourage all parents and guardians to make themselves aware of what their children are up to on the Internet and discuss privacy and safety issues with them. Public discussion areas on the Network are not private. Any information posted by your child in such areas may be seen, collected and used by others and may result in unsolicited messages or other unwanted attention! The Family Health Network can not control this. You should instruct your child not to post any such information without first seeking your permission. Your child posts at their own risk!

## 8\. Questions and Concerns

You should contact The Family Health Network immediately if you have any questions or concerns relating to our Privacy Policy or any other aspect of the Network. The Family Health Network appreciates your input and will give serious consideration to any issues raised and take any action we consider necessary to improve the services provided by the Network.

## 9\. Alterations to this Privacy Policy

The Family Health Network reserves the right to add to, remove and alter any of the features of the Network to improve User enjoyment and satisfaction of all aspects of the Network. It may be necessary for us to alter this Privacy Policy from time to time to reflect these changes. The Family Health Network reserves the right to alter this Privacy Policy at any time by posting an undated version on the Network. You should refer to this Policy on a regular basis so you are aware of any changes.

## 10\. Specific Conditions

Some sites on the Network may be operated in conjunction with other individuals or entities. They may have special Terms and Conditions and Privacy Policies which differ from those of The Family Health Network. Where they differ the more specific terms will apply.

You should familiarize yourself with the relevant Web site's Terms and Conditions and Privacy Policy before using their site or disclosing any of your personal information to them.

Back to home page
